Hello. Yes, I'll get her.
Yes,
I'll tell her. All right. Bye.
I've got a message
for you. A secret one.
[ Blows Raspberry ] Aah!
When I was but 13 or so,
I went into a golden land.
Chimbarozo Cotopaxi
took me by the hand.
Over the Orinoco. Across
the blazing Kalahari Desert.
Through the untamed
grasslands of the Veldt.
What is it? What did she say?
What did she say that
for? It's all right. I don't mind.
Everything's
going to be all right.
** [ Woman Humming ]
** [ Humming Continues ]
[ Groans ]
Hils, wake up.
Mummy's made a
new song for us to play.
B-flat. Listen.
Big waves,
rolling in three-four time.
And when you hear me
change to the major chord,
I want you to dive
down under the sea.
Dive down under the waves.
Little silvery fishes swimming
in and out of the seaweed...
in six-eight time.
And... watch out.
Here comes the shark.
[ Pounds Keys, Roaring ]
[ Roaring Continues
] [ Girls Laughing ]
"Dear Mrs. Du Pre,
we are planning to broadcast...
a children's performance of
the Toy Symphony by..." Haydn.
Very good.
"We would be delighted if you would conduct
and Hilary would play the flute part."
It's from the BBC. Jolly good.
Jolly good. Well done, Hullabaloo.
Ha! What about me?
If you practice hard enough,
maybe next time.
I want to come this time.
I want to be with Hilary.
Well,
couldn't she just come along for the ride?
- It's an orchestra, Derek, not a Clapham omnibus.
- [ Blows Raspberry ]
Jackie,
that is quite uncalled-for.
You're spoiling
Hilary's special day.
If Jackie can't come,
I won't go.
** [ Classical ]
** [ Stops ] Follow the score.
Don't gawp at the soloist.
I really can't apologize enough. Oh,
not at all.
Worth any amount of
trouble to get young Hilary.
She's really very special. Yes,
I realize that.
Your sister's a remarkable
girl. You must be very proud.
Oh, we all are,
terribly proud. Good-bye.
If you want to be with Hilary,
you have to play as well as Hilary.
If you want to be together, you've got to
be as good as each other. Understand?
Yes.
** [ Cello ]
Supper's ready.
So I think we should leave
some money on the doorstep...
for the burglar to take,
so he wouldn't steal anymore.
What do you think? Um...
Well,
I think that... [ Humming ]
[ Woman ] I want you to
do all the sums on the page.
And then I want you
to... [ Dialogue Fades ]
[ Woman ] And the first prize
goes to the Du Pre sisters,
Jacqueline and
Hilary. Well done.
[ Applause ] There's one
for you and one for you.
[ Applause Continues ]
Shall I take that for you? * La,
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, *
* La, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la, *
la, la, la, la *
* La, la, la, la, la, la, la *
[ Instruments Tuning ]
[ Humming Continues ]
[ Woman ] In the
woodwind category,
a very clear winner,
with the highest number of points...
ever awarded in this
section of this festival.
Hilary Du Pre.
Well done.
We had no difficulty at all in choosing
the winner in the string section,
even though we
were a little unnerved...
by the candidate's rather
overemphatic bodily movements.
I think this must
be the first time...
that our winning soloists
have been sisters.
The judges were unanimous...
in choosing Miss
Jacqueline Du Pre.
[ Audience Cheering ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have plenty more awards,
so I'd be grateful if you all could
sit down... [ Dialogue Fades ]
[ Cheering, Applause Continue ]
She does bob about a bit.
She looks like one of
these bobby-soxer types.
I'm afraid that's my fault.
They did a lot of musical
movement when they were younger.
Can we have a picture,
please? You too, sir.
That's lovely. Yeah.
You give me some
nice big smiles.
Hils! Hils!
Come over.
This is one of yours too? Does
she play? [ Mother ] Oh, yes.
Hilary won as well,
didn't you, dear?
We can have a family portrait.
Hold your flute up. Smile then.
Your sister's a remarkable
girl. You must be very proud.
Oh, yes, we are, terribly proud.
Smile then.
[ Speaking,
[ Speaking, Indistinct ]
Well, be good.
We'll collect you in an hour.
Be good. Yes.
Now, let's see what you can do.
An hour today and
then see how we go.
Oh.
Well, now, this is nice.
** [ Cello ]
No.
Try that... that lifting,
that upbeat before the three quavers...
with an up bow like... like so.
[ Jackie ] I like him.
He's my cello daddy.
I want to come every
day. Can I come every day?
Do you mind? We
shall have to get a car.
[ Flute Hits Window ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Door Shuts ]
** [ Continues ]
That's it.
She's ready.
Mrs. Du Pre, what do you think of
a debut recital at the Wigmore Hall?
Marvelous. I've spoken
to Ibbs and Tillot.
They'll handle the
publicity and the tickets.
And to Ernest Lush. He'll
accompany her on the piano.
Oh.
- [ Playing Off-key ]
- She's playing flat.
** [ Stops ]
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm afraid
that my "A" string has come loose,
and I'm going to have to
re-string my cello and start again.
[ Audience Murmuring ]
Well, at least it wasn't
my G-string. ** [ Cello ]
[ Applause, Cheering ]
I do wish she'd
keep that head still.
It looks so flamboyant,
all that hair flying about the place.
[ Chattering,
Laughter ] There she is.
Oh. That was wonderful.
They want me to play at a wedding,
in Italy.
It's a princess's wedding.
You will come? I'd be
terrified on my own. Oh, Jack...
Congratulations. You
were wonderful. Thank you.
Um, excuse me, everyone. Attention,
please. Thank you.
Jackie's debut went very well.
Um, I'm sure you would agree.
And to mark the occasion,
a very generous friend,
who wishes to remain anonymous,
has offered her this.
It's one of the finest
cellos ever made.
It's called The Davidov.
The magic is in the varnish.
So you must keep it away
from extremes of temperature.
Another problem
is the insurance.
So don't let it get
out of your sight.
It will give you the world,
Jackie,
but you must give it yourself.
[ Speaking Mock Italian ]
[ Mock Italian Continues ]
Bellissimo! Si, bellissimo!
Bellissimo! Si, fortissimo!
[ Laughing ] Shh, shh.
[ Glasses Clink ]
[ Champagne Bubbling ]
[ Whispering ] This is
so loud. [ Both Laughing ]
Okay. Here's to Hilary and
Jackie and all who sail in her.
[ Snickers ]
Mm.
Look, Hils.
[ Hilary ] We're in Heaven.
[ Woman ] Oh,
put that bloody light out.
[ Bell Tolling ]
Excuse me. Have
you seen my sister?
Is your sister Jacqueline Du Pre? Yes,
that's right.
She'll be in Berlin by now. She's
playing The Haydn Cello Concerto in C.
Oh.
Are you going back to London? Yes,
I suppose so.
[ Tolling Continues ]
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
** [ Flute ]
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
What is this blasted
jigging about?
Stand still, girl. Stand still.
It is impossible to produce a proper
tone without proper deportment.
[ Sighs ] You have no technique.
That's all right.
Technique can be taught.
We just have to go back to
the beginning and start again.
- Cancel any concert dates you may have outstanding.
- Yes, Mr. Bentley.
Oh, Hilary,
how's your marvelous sister?
I'm not sure. She's away
at the moment. In Russia.
Oh.
[ Stations Tuning ]
** [ Flute ] That's it, old boy.
Keep trying. [ Static ]
[ Man Speaking
Russian ] That's it!
[ Speaking Continues ]
Ooh! Felt that.
Oh! Now, listen. Well done, boy.
What is it? That
is Radio Moscow.
This is what Jackie will be hearing
if she's listening to the wireless.
[ All Chuckling ]
No.
No. No! No! No!
Instead of
rehearsing this piece,
I just want you to
practice playing B-flat.
Just the note B-flat? The note.
Just the note.
Parcel from Jacks, everybody!
Help? Come on. Open it.
Can't open it. Here. Here,
here, here. Let me.
[ Mother ] It's her washing.
I suppose it must be difficult getting
her washing done in a foreign country.
Good afternoon, Madam.
My niece is a student... [ Continues,
Indistinct ]
Ah, Miss Du Pre. Yes?
I was wondering whether I
could book you for a concert.
- It's not me you want. It's my sister.
- But you're Hilary Du Pre.
The flautist. Well,
it's you I want. Yes.
The Bach,
B Minor. Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm not allowed to play
concerts until after my exam.
- Well, when's your exam?
- Now, as a matter of fact.
Well, in that case, I'll wait.
Please.
Good.
Would you like to try that for us again,
please, Hilary?
Again.
Again!
Uh, Miss Du Pre?
** [ Cello ]
Oh, do I get my booking?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Well,
you ran off. I followed you home.
You don't mind, do you?
No,
as a matter of fact.
I'd ask you in, but, um,
it's a bit awkward.
My sister's just come home.
Well...
Best go in.
What do you think you're doing?
Well,
if you're not going to invite me to tea,
I shall just have to make
a nuisance of myself.
You...
Oh! You know... I'm starving.
Whoo! Come here.
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
[ Gasps ] Hils!
Hello. Who's this? Kiffer.
Kiffer Finzi. I'm
in love with Hilary.
[ Laughing ] And you're
Hilary's sister? What do you do?
I'm a musician.
Oh, following in Hils' footsteps,
are you? You any good?
Hello. Kiffer Finzi.
Very pleased to meet you.
You don't mind if I start,
do you?
- Exams really do give you an appetite.
- Your exam... How did it go?
- Oh...
- Famously. She's been offered professional bookings.
Five quid to do The Bach B Minor
next week in Newbury. Isn't that right?
Yes.
You must be very proud of her. Yes,
I am.
These are delicious. It's
absolutely throwing it down outside.
We got soaked. Shall
I be mum? All right.
There. Oh, a nice cup of tea.
He's an utter scream.
It was so embarrassing.
So, have you been with him?
[ Laughing ] Of course not.
Why? Have you
been with somebody?
I'm thinking my answer,
and you're going to have to read my mind.
All right.
[ Gasps ] Oh,
my Lordy, you have.
You study in scarlet.
What about you,
Hils? Been with anyone.
Well,
you'll have to read my mind.
Oh, poor Hils. Maybe one day.
Then again, maybe not.
"Hilary Du Pre is a flautist of immense
expressive as well as technical ability.
She obviously has a
great future ahead of her."
Does it mention Jackie? Why should
it mention Jackie? She wasn't playing.
Might I ask you to
keep your voice down?
Jackie's asleep, and we don't
like to disturb her. What, she's here?
Yes, she's in bed. Well,
she should get up, read your review.
- No, you mustn't wake her. Hilary, tell him.
- [ Hilary ] Kiffer.
- Where is he going?
- Up! Up out of that bed!
[ Jackie Screaming ] Hilary, your
friend is making rather a lot of noise.
[ Screaming
Continues ] Up! Up! Up!
Look, read.
Oh, we're off to the pictures.
Can I come? No,
you can't come. It's a date.
We're going to see
Jules et Jim. Shh.
- Sounds French. Where's it playing?
- In France.
It's by Francois Truffaut, and it's
playing at the Scala in Wardour Street.
That's in Soho. Yes.
I thought we could go
to Maison Bertaux first,
seeing as we're
in a French mood.
You do realize that there are white
slavers working in that area, hmm?
No self-respecting man would
ask a woman to go to such a place.
It's out of the question.
I'm sorry. It's completely
out of the question.
Well,
no chance of a lift then. Come on.
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
Jacks.
Kiffer's asked me
to marry him. What?
Kiffer's asked me to marry him.
Well? What do you think?
Well, that's just silly.
Look, Hils,
you don't have to marry him.
Do you know what that is?
That, my dear, is a Dutch cap.
It's a contraceptive.
Is it really?
How did you get
it? Doc fitted me up.
Oh, come on, Hils.
Let's get a flat together
and go bonkers.
We could have all the men we
wanted to. I'm going to marry Kiffer.
I love him.
He loves me. He
does not love you.
He just wants to get
into your knickers.
You don't have to get married
every time you fancy a screw.
That's what these are
for. I want to get married.
Well, you can't marry him.
You can't just leave
me. I'm not leaving you.
You're not here anymore.
You never will be again.
- Haven't you heard? I'm giving up the cello.
- Oh, don't be silly.
I can do what I want. You don't
know anything apart from the cello.
I don't know anything
apart from the flute.
We're babies,
Jacks. Kiffer laughs at me.
Then why are you marrying him?
Because he makes
me feel special.
Well,
that's a big swizz because the truth is...
you're not special.
I thought you'd be happy for me.
[ Footsteps Departing ]
This is nice.
Hi. Good God.
What on earth are you wearing?
[ Speaking With Accent ] Oh,
it's fab. Danny bought it for me.
This is Danny, by the way. Danny,
this is Daddy. Daddy-O.
[ Chuckling ]
Barenboim? I thought
he was from Argentina.
Surely that must be a German
name. I think it must be Jewish.
Oh. Oh, dear.
I had a large breakfast
this morning... He's a pig.
But I have got plenty more. Piers,
take this off.
Anyway, Mummy,
we're really desperate to get married,
but Lord knows when
we're going to have the time.
Of course. It's best not to
rush these things, darling.
Well,
I'm completely booked up until May.
And then Danny's
booked up until... June.
He's such a show-off,
but he's very handsome, isn't he?
We only really meet in airports. We're
going to do more joint bookings together.
Sort of like a duo, like the Beatles.
There are four Beatles actually.
Are there? Mm-hmm.
Anyway, when we do get married,
we're going to get married somewhere
like the Wailing Wall in Jerusalem.
Don't you have to be Jewish to
be married at the Wailing Wall?
I'm going to be Jewish.
I'm having lessons already.
Instruction, not lessons.
So, what do you think?
- Why are you talking funny?
- [ Laughs ]
Am I?
Nobody becomes Jewish. You
can't just convert to Judaism.
Bye-bye,
darling. Leave it to me.
Honestly,
I can sort it out. Oh, uh...
[ Door Closes ] Jackie can't
possibly be Jewish, for God's sake.
She's blonde.
Oh.
[ Man On TV ] They call them the
Arthur and Guinevere of music's Camelot.
The blossoming romance between Jacqueline
Du Pre and the Argentinean pianist,
Daniel Barenboim, has taken the
world of classical music by storm.
Up a bit higher. That's it.
I can see them now... the greatest
musical talents of their generation.
Miss Du Pre astonished
the British public...
with her brilliant rendition
of Elgar's Cello Concerto.
- Piers!
- Dressed for a triumphant series of...
[ Hilary ] You've ruined it now.
[ Man On TV ] The fabulous couple
has just announced their engagement.
Miss Du Pre is
converting to Judaism,
and they plan to wed in
Barenboim's adopted home of Israel...
in the golden city of Jerusalem.
[ All ] Mazeltov!
[ People Shouting ]
[ Applause ]
[ Applause, Cheering ]
[ Rooster Crowing ]
[ Whistles ] Both asleep.
Coming.
Huh!
Mmm. Mm-hmm.
[ Laughing ]
Aah! Aah! Aah! Oh,
it's freezing!
Yeah, well, cold fingers are very
stimulating. They're bloody well not.
Shh.
What?
[ Laughing ] Okay.
Mind your head. [ Roars ]
[ Hilary Laughing ]
Aah! [ Laughing ]
Your nose is cold too!
Someone's coming. They can't be.
Well, they are, you know.
It's Jackie.
[ Laughing ]
Oh,
darling. [ Car Engine Starts ]
Oh!
Now, why didn't you tell us?
Do I have to walk all
the way down there?
Oh, come on.
[ Laughs ]
[ Kiffer ] More wine?
[ Jackie ] Okay.
[ Hilary ] Yes, please.
So, Hilary, listen.
Oh,
no. I've forgotten it now. Shit!
How does it go?
Oh,
I know this. I know this. Yes!
Dvorjak! Dvorjak!
Carnival Overture.
No, no,
no. Absolutely not fair. Yes!
You two are telepathic.
It's true. It's true.
- Oh, rubbish. - Do another one.
- [ Hilary ] - [ Hilary ] All right.
- [ Laughing ]
Okay. [ Laughing ]
Are you listening? Yeah,
all right.
I know this. this is Deus
Natales by Kiffer's father.
You should know that.
All right,
go on. Do another one.
Okay, um...
Don't tap it. Just think it.
All right.
That's "You Really
Got Me" by the Kinks.
[ Laughing ] Absolutely.
You're just saying that. No,
it's true.
We always know what
the other one is thinking.
- You know what I'm thinking now, don't you, sis?
- Not really.
- Yes, you do. - No, I don't.
I'll tell you. No.
I mean, just tell me.
[ Whispering ] I want
to sleep with Kiffer.
You don't mind, do you, sis?
We always did say that we'd
share everything, remember?
What?
What is it? Nothing. I think
we should all go to bed.
[ Blows Raspberry ] I don't want to
go to bed. I could stay up all night.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Moans ]
[ Hilary ] You have
to be very careful...
because it's very easy
to stand on worms.
Why don't you look around there?
I think you might
be standing on one.
[ Door Closes ]
I'm just going over to the
Williams' place for cheese, doll.
- I'll come with you.
- I thought you had jet lag.
Well, the walk will help.
You two go together and I
can get on with the gutters.
Fine.
- Actually, I'd just as soon stay here.
- Me too. Settled then.
Kiffer goes off for the cheese,
and we stay here.
I'll get the fucking cheese,
all right.
[ Kids Speaking, Indistinct ]
- I think you should go with her.
- Why?
'Cause she doesn't know the way.
Jackie!
Jackie! [ Jackie Crying ]
[ Crying Continues ]
Jackie?
Jackie.
Get away from me!
You don't love me!
No fucker loves me!
All I want is a fuck.
Jackie. Jackie.
[ Screams ]
Come on. All I want is a fucking fuck,
for fuck's sake!
It's okay. [ Sobbing ]
It's all right.
No.
[ Chuckling ] No.
- We have to.
- No, we don't have to.
- Why would we have to? Why would anyone have to?
- Because she's my sister.
Well, you'll find that this
is not the sort of thing...
that sisters normally
ask one another.
- Because I'm scared.
- Yes, well, she doesn't scare me.
I'm sure it would
just be the once.
[ Scoffs ] Just the once,
huh? Any particular position?
She just needs proof. Proof of what,
for God's sake, Hils?
Proof that somebody loves her.
She just went.
Didn't say a word. Didn't...
cancel her engagements.
How does she seem to you?
Well,
she has been acting a little oddly.
[ Danny ] Why,
it's beautiful. I can see why you wanted...
to come here instead
of Los Angeles.
Don't worry about the cancellations,
by the way.
I've seen to them.
Everyone was very
understanding. No one...
wants to put pressure on you,
so...
don't worry.
[ Hilary ] Did you...
So...
[ Hilary ] Which is the
daddy? Which one?
[ Kiffer ] Uh, there's a slate mine
on the other side of the mountain.
[ Hilary ] Kiffer,
look what Theresa's found.
Will you excuse me a moment?
[ Chattering ]
I was thinking.
If Kiffer and Hilary can do it,
so can we.
We could buy a house near here,
if you like.
It would cost next to nothing.
We could have all we needed.
We could have a little studio,
rehearsal rooms, phones...
We could have a helipad.
What do you say?
[ Blows Raspberry ]
I try to give her
everything she wants. I-I...
I don't know what she wants.
Do you know what she wants?
Not really.
Look after her,
won't you, Kiffer?
[ Engine Starts ]
That's better.
It's just us again.
** [ Jackie Humming ]
** [ Humming Continues ]
** [ Humming Continues ] [
Bed Hitting Wall Rhythmically ]
You know you can't have toast. I
don't know why you keep asking.
Daddy, I want toast. Toast?
Toast? I want toast
too. Can we have toast?
Um, well, I haven't had a
chance to light the fire yet.
Well, then,
we'll light the fire, won't we?
Come on. Let's light the fire. Okay,
here.
There. Take some of these...
and put them on the fire.
[ Dishes Clanking ]
I feel a million
dollars this morning.
That was exactly what
the doctor ordered.
[ Sighs ] Oh, thank you, Hils.
You don't mind, do you?
No, of course not.
Well, here we all are.
Wouldn't it be wonderful if
we could stay like this forever?
[ Chattering ]
Come on. Put some
more logs on the fire.
[ Jackie ] Come on! [ Kiffer
] Come on! A bit higher!
[ Jackie Shouting ]
Come on! Throw the ball!
Throw it! Throw it! Throw it!
[ Kiffer Laughing ] Come
on! [ Jackie ] Come on!
[ Jackie Yelling Excitedly ] [
Kiffer ] Foul, everybody! Come on.
[ Both Shouting ]
- [ Jackie Shrieks ]
- Come on. Let's go.
Here, Kif.
Come on.
What... What are you doing?
I'm kissing you.
It's me, Hils.
I know. [ Kisses ]
You're my wife.
[ Both Breathing Heavily ]
What about Jacks?
What about her?
She'll wake up. Look!
I don't care.
[ Moaning ] [
Breathing Heavily ]
[ Thud ] Shh. Shh. Kiffer, shh.
[ Bed Thudding ] Kiffer! Kiffer!
Kiffer.
[ Sighs Deeply ]
** [ Cello ] Oh, God!
Kiffer. Shh.
Stop. Get off me! Get off me!
Get off me! She'll never
talk to me again now.
You've got to start
saying no to her.
The more you give her,
the more she wants.
You've got to start saying no,
Hilary.
** [ Cello Continues ]
I've given you everything.
Ever since we were little,
everything you've asked for, I've said yes.
Jackie, listen.
Jackie!
Jackie...
I'm sorry.
[ Girls Giggling ]
[ Hilary ] Chimbarozo
Cotopaxi took me by the hand.
Over the Orinoco. [ Screams ]
Across the blazing desert.
Through the untamed grasslands.
We're in heaven.
[ Woman ] Oh,
put that bloody light out.
Psst! Psst!
Come,
we must go. You have a plane.
- What?
- Your plane to Germany for your concert tonight.
- What about my sister?
- She will be taken to her England plane.
It's all arranged.
You must hurry.
** [ Cello ]
[ Chattering ]
Very good. Romantic.
We understand this.
Really? I'm afraid I don't
understand a bloody word, frankly.
Please? [ Chuckles ]
Danke. Bitte.
Uh,Ich bin ein Hamburger.
[ Mock German ]
[ Mock German Continues ]
Ja. Wunderbar!
Oh, um, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Wrong number. Enschuldigan.
Hello,
Mummy. Is Hilary there? Can...
Oh, sorry. S-Sorry,
wrong number. Sorry.
[ Bell Dings ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Fantastico. Fantastico, Querida.
Casals was in the audience
tonight. He was most impressed.
We would be honored if
you would join us for supper.
Oh, I'd love to.
Only,
the problem is-is that I stink.
Excuse me?
Well, the sweat just runs
off me when I'm playing.
What about Pablo? Does he have the
same problem? Look. [ Gasps ]Dios mio!
Excuse me. Um, my clothes are dirty,
and I'd like to wash them.
Uh, wash? Yes?
Uh, dirty? Washing?
Si. Lavadero. Well,
there's no plug and it's too small.
No. Lavadero. Lavelo alli.
[ Mock Spanish ] No entiendo,
senora. Lavelo alli.
Lavelo estos alli en lavadero.
[ Mock Spanish ] Lo siento mucho,
senora. Lo siento mucho, senora.
Lo siento mucho, senora. No,
no. Is it a washing machine?
¿Ay! ¡Esos ingleses!
[ Creaking ]
[ Creaking Continues ]
- ** [ Emits Creaking
Note ] - Shut up!
** [ Cello ]
[ Woman ] The maestro
is pleased to see you.
He thinks you are
going to be a great cellist.
He wants to know if all is well.
Do you have happiness here?
Gosh,
yes. Heaps of it. It's just, um...
It's just the cello.
Well, it's silly, really,
but I just don't want
to be a cellist after all.
Well, I never asked to be a cellist,
you see. It's all just a big cock-up.
One day I was just playing, and the next
day, I was booked up for the next two years.
I hate the cello,
if you want to know.
I think I understand this wrong.
[ Sighs ] Yes. Thank you.
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Tolling Continues ]
Home.
This is what my
home smells like.
[ Wind Gusting ]
[ Door Slams ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Screams ]
Hello. Who's this?
Kiffer. Kiffer Finzi.
I'm in love with
Hilary. [ Chuckles ]
I shan't be very late.
I came back to see you.
I shan't be long.
[ Hilary ] It was terribly
funny! [ Kiffer Laughing ]
[ Jackie ] I'm
going to get a job,
and I'm going to be an
ordinary person like you.
[ Hilary ] Couldn't be
ordinary in a million years!
And you don't know
anything apart from your cello.
I don't know anything
apart from the flute.
Jackie, we're babies.
Kiffer laughs at me.
Then why are you marrying him?
Because he makes
me feel special.
[ Jackie ] You don't understand that,
because...
you don't have anybody
to make you feel special.
Well, that's a big swizz.
Because the truth is
that you're not special.
If you think that being
an ordinary person...
is any easier than being an
extraordinary one, you're wrong.
If you didn't have that cello to
prop you up, you'd be nothing.
** [ Piano: Lively ]
[ Indistinct Chattering ]
** [ Ends ] Who's that?
Oh, Freud.
You like Freud?
Yes.
Well, he'd be a lot better if he hadn't
invented the atom bomb, though, wouldn't he?
Are you Jacqueline Du Pre? Yes,
I am.
I've heard about you.
I'm Daniel Barenboim.
Oh, I've heard about you too.
Really? What have you heard?
I heard that you
had glandular fever.
That's right.
Well, it's very infectious, isn't it,
so you'd better keep your distance.
Oh, it's not infectious,
it's contagious.
You have to have bodily
contact with the other person.
Oh, so you can talk to me,
but you can't kiss me.
[ Woman ] Jackie?
You left this in the cab.
Silly girl. Thank you.
So you are a musician. Yes,
I am a musician.
You know very well I'm a musician.
A very famous musician, actually.
Well,
you don't look like a musician.
Really? So what are
musicians supposed to look like?
They're not usually so blonde.
[ Woman ] Danny, we should go.
I have to go.
I'd love to talk to you
sometime about glandular fever.
[ Party Chatter
Continues ] ** [ Cello ]
Paderewski medal.
Beethoven medal.
You name it. [ Chuckles ]
Well,
I won a talent
contest in Camden.
Mm-Hmm? And I won at Purley.
Where's Purley? Oh,
you wouldn't know it.
Moscow.
I won in Moscow. Hmm.
I made Miss Mouncey cry.
Who's Miss Mouncey?
Who is Miss Mouncey?
[ Chuckles ]
She is my math teacher.
What about you?
Did you ever make anyone cry?
Mmm, no,
I never made anyone cry.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Whispers ] Thank you.
I'm sorry I treated
you so badly.
I should have known
you'll never let me down.
** [ Beethoven ]
** [ Switches To
"You Really Got Me" ]
** [ Ends ] [ Both Chuckling ]
Now,
that... That's how to play Beethoven.
** [ Beethoven ] It's too slow.
You're coming in too slow.
No,
you're too fast. You're throwing it away.
No, you'll have to do it again.
I think I decide the tempo.
Are you all right? Yeah,
I've just got cold hands.
Okay.
Listen to that. It sounds
like you're running for a bus.
I've never run for
a bus in my life.
[ Door Opens ]
To keep your hands warm. Oh,
Danny!
She's very vigorous with the bow,
huh?
So there has to be an unusual
amount of room under the arm, here.
And... [ Chuckles ]
Sweat. Sweat is
the main problem.
So that the seams have to be
a lot stronger than normal, huh?
I understand.
** [ Orchestral ]
** [ Stops ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
I'm sorry. It's all right.
They'll love it.
[ Audience Applauding ]
[ Danny ] How are we
going to do the thing...
without those two
guys? [ Chuckling ]
[ Both Chuckling, Chattering ]
[ Danny ] I've called for
him three or four times.
Have you seen my pills
anywhere? I've lost my pills.
I don't know where your pills are. Oh,
come on.
[ Bottles Crashing ] Shit.
Don't worry about the pills.
I can't play without the
pills. Of course you can.
The pills have no effect
on you whatsoever.
I found them.
Danny,
would you still love me if I couldn't play?
What? I said,
You wouldn't be you if you
couldn't play. No, I want to know.
"O body swayed to music.
"O brightening glance.
"How can we know...
the dancer from the dance?"
Don't you wish sometimes you couldn't play,
that you could just be ordinary?
And what?
Live in the country
baking bread?
Feeding chickens?
Playing once a year
with a bunch of amateurs?
How dare you insult my sister
like that! I wasn't insulting her.
I was just saying... Well,
at least she chose her life.
Not like you and me.
We're just trained freaks!
Look, let's just get in the
cab and then talk about it.
I wasn't being rude.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Hilary ] Oh,
why didn't you tell us you were coming?
[ Door Latch Clicks ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Urinating ]
** [ Orchestral ]
** [ Mournful ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Crashing ]
- [ Hissing ] - [
Loud Screeching ]
[ Hissing,
Screeching Subside ] ** [ Continues ]
** [ Fades ]
[ Applause: Distorted ]
[ Applause Ends ]
I can't get up. What?
I can't get up.
Give it to me.
[ Whispered Murmuring ]
Danny,
I've got a fatal illness.
But you mustn't worry,
'cause I've got it very mildly.
[ Sighs ]
Look, uh,
what if she won't see you?
Well,
of course she'll see me. I'm her sister.
[ Jackie Chattering ]
So lovely. The
people are so kind.
I have all these flowers and cards
and chocolates. I'm going to get so fat.
You know, I'm so relieved that
it's only MS. I know it's serious,
but I thought I was going mad!
Hello, Jacks.
It's good to see you.
Hilary.
This... [ Chuckles
] [ Vase Clanks ]
My sister here will tell you. This
country bumpkin here is my sister.
This is Dame Margot
Fonteyn. She's a friend of mine.
It's so nice to meet you,
Dame Margot. Pleased.
My sister will tell you. I was
behaving in the strangest way.
But you know,
all that's happening...
is that my nerve endings are
damaged or something. Right.
And I might have to go
into a wheelchair. Oh, no.
But not for ages.
It takes years.
And it happens in fits and starts,
and they're on the brink of a cure anyway.
Well, who'll look after you,
then?
Well, it's just Danny's so busy,
isn't he, and...
Well, the flat's all wrong. It's just Kif
and I have talked about it, and we...
Dame Margot has very kindly
offered to lend me her flat.
[ Jackie ] You see,
it's in Kensington.
Well, I can't really be hidden
away in the country, can I?
Hilary keeps chickens.
She used to be a musician,
but now it's all chickens and children,
isn't it, Hils?
I would so like to have children.
Hilary's got heaps of them.
In fact,
if you want to get yourself...
impregnated,
you should ask her hubby.
He's extremely fertile, and if you
ask her nicely, she'll lend him to you.
She's never been quite right
since she went to Russia, you know.
I think... Do be quiet, Derek.
You don't think this means
she'll have to stop playing?
No. Of course not.
Bye, Daddy. Bye-bye, sweetheart.
Of course, it's all frightful,
but it's better than going bonkers.
I was sure she
was going bonkers.
** [ Cello ]
Okay, I'll do this one again.
Careful. Careful.
Ooh, my God.
That's very good! [
Chuckling ] Shut up!
That's good! That's good! You know,
that's good!
I'm going to fall
off. [ Chuckles ]
I got offered a job today.
I thought you already had a job.
Move over. I can't move over.
All right. I'll move you over.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
Artistic Director...
of the orchestre de Paris.
Oh.
[ Sighs ] Oh.
In many ways,
it would be better than now.
You know,
I'd always be in one place.
Not in Manchester one night
and Chicago the next, you know?
You are always
in the same place.
Yes.
Paris.
I know. If it were London...
Oh,
of course you should do it. Of course.
Paris isn't that far. You
could come home a lot.
We'll think about it. It will give
me a chance to practice my French.
I've been working very hard
on my languages, actually.
That's good.
Joder.You know what that is?
I think so. [ Chuckles ]
It's Spanish for "fuck."
It's Swahili.
[ Car Engine Starts ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
I just wondered how you
were getting on without him.
I'm not without him. He
comes home every weekend.
Anyway, it'll be easier once
I start playing properly again.
Besides,
I get heaps of visitors.
Look at all the flowers. Lovely.
What's that?
Oh, that's my new pushchair.
But you don't need
a wheelchair yet?
Oh, I see.
I suppose that if I ate
differently or I exercised more...
none of this would be happening.
It's all my fault. Is that it?
No, I was just surprised,
that's all.
Oh,
it's all my fault. It's all psychological.
If it's psychological,
it's your fault. You're my mother.
I'm sure it's nobody's fault.
Don't eat those cakes,
Daddy. They're for my visitors.
Sorry, Jacks.
** [ Cello, Discordant ]
Am I a cello genius?
[ Danny Chuckles ]
You know you are.
Danny,
I just want to play again.
[ Phone Line Crackles ]
I'll play the fucking triangle. I
just want to make music again.
Okay. Leave it to me.
** [ Orchestral: Lively ]
Oh,
my goodness! It's me! [ Chuckles ]
- [ Chuckles ] - [ Applauding ]
[ Applause Fades ]
[ Child Laughing ]
[ Danny Chattering ]
Teaching...
can be just as rewarding as playing,
in its own way.
Don't you think? What?
I said, teaching can be as
rewarding as playing, in its own way.
Where's Hilary?
She had to leave
early. It's a long drive.
I want Hilary. Right.
I'll go see if the car's here. Margaret,
the flowers.
[ Whooshing Sound
] [ Jackie ] Danny.
Mm-hmm? I think
my hearing's going.
Very brave of her,
when you think about it.
Can't so much as bang a drum
unless the whole world's looking at her.
[ Engine Starts ] I'm sorry. I
really think we ought to go see her.
If we go back now,
it'll be quieter. I'd like to see her.
I wish you would go and see her. You
haven't been to see her in such a long time.
She'll have heaps of visitors,
and she doesn't want to see me.
- She seems so unhappy.
- Well, Mother, that is hardly surprising.
But she was happy,
and now she says she wasn't.
I thought... if you
could show her this...
What for? Well, as evidence.
It might remind her.
Mummy,
everyone smiles for photographs.
Hello. Danny? Hi. How are you?
Okay.
I'm missing you. [
Breathing Heavy ]
Listen,
I won't be able to get home this weekend.
[ Sighs ] Mahler.
I've always hated Mahler.
Now I hate him more.
Perhaps next week
I'll get home. I hope so.
[ Baby Crying ] What was that?
What? That noise.
- What sort of noise?
- [ Baby Crying ]
[ Sighs ] Oh, it's nothing.
It's probably my
hearing playing up again.
It sounded like a baby crying.
I see.
It must be my hearing playing up again,
mustn't it?
I'll call you later.
You bastard.
Where's... Hilary? She's...
The children have got a virus,
and they didn't
want you to catch it.
Typical.
When...
you play,
everyone... loves you.
When...
you stop,
you're alone.
I'm sure it's not quite that bad,
Jacks.
Look... Look at this.
Music and movement.
[ Crying ]
Oh... Oh, for heaven's sake,
stop... crying.
**
** [ Cello ]
** [ Continues ]
** [ Stops ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Grunting ]
I don't understand
what she wants.
I think she's in
some sort of pain.
There are things you
want to say. I can see that.
But you cannot say them. Or
we cannot understand them.
But there is someone
who hears your thoughts.
Do not worry. God hears them
all. He hears your every thought.
[ Screams ]
[ Gasps ]
Yes?
Oh, it's Hilary,
Jacqueline's sister.
Oh,
I see. This is my brother Piers.
- Hello. - [ People Chattering ]
Isn't this shocking
weather? Yes.
Well, where's she going?
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Man Laughing ]
[ Grunting ] I can't get anything
down. I've been trying for days.
Can I try?
Shh, shh, shh. That's it.
That's it. Up you go. Up you go.
Come on.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
Got you where I want you now.
Come on.
[ Blows Raspberry ]
You're still in there somewhere then,
Jacks, huh?
Come on.
Eh? You still in
there somewhere?
[ Panting ]
Good girl.
When you love someone,
pictures of them stay with
you all the time in your heart.
Pictures of the way you think
of them when you think of them.
With Mummy, it's that day
you broke the drum at the BBC.
Whenever you think
you've lost that person,
you start with a picture and
then you find them again.
Do you want to know what I
think of when I think of you?
When people say
"Jacqueline Du Pre" to me,
I think of a day on the
beach a long time ago,
long before you
could play the cello.
Before that Jacqueline
Du Pre or this one.
And we were playing a game.
When I was but 13 or so,
I went into a golden land.
Chimbarozo Cotopaxi
took me by the hand.
Over the Orinoco.
Across the blazing
Kalahari Desert.
Through the untamed grasslands
of the Veldt. Over the steppes...
And home.
Do you remember what you
said to me that day, Jackie?
You said... that everything
was going to be all right.
And in the end it was.
[ Man ] ...hundreds of
roads were blocked...
and large parts of the rail
network are out of action.
The Home Secretary is chairing
an emergency meeting of ministers...
to discuss ways of
dealing with the emergency.
The cellist Jacqueline Du Pre
has died at her London home.
She was 42.
Jacqueline Du Pre began to
learn the cello at the age of five...
and won several awards before
rising to the top of her profession.
She will be particularly remembered for
her performances of Elgar's Cello Concerto.
Stop the car, Piers.
Stop the car.
Oh, God!
[ Sobbing ] Jackie!
Hils, where are you going?
[ Hilary ] When I
was but 13 or so,
I went into a golden land.
Chimbarozo Cotopaxi
took me by the hand.
Over the Orinoco.
Across the blazing
Kalahari desert.
Through the untamed
grasslands of the Veldt.
Over the steppes...
And home.
What do you want?
Nothing. Just to see you.
Bye.
Jackie.
I just wanted to tell you...
that everything's
going to be all right.
Subtitles Diego Moraes(oakislandtk)
www.opensubtitles.org